<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debayan Ganguly</title>
    <description>Explore and Unleash Possibilities</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 21:48:25 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 21:48:25 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting a Company with Co-Founders, or going Solo?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;https://media.giphy.com/media/fQZX2aoRC1Tqw/giphy.gif&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have an idea, and you want to build something. Question is, should you do it alone, or with co-founders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is broken down into three parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First section talks about Benefits and Drawbacks of Co-Founders, second one the same about Solo Founders, and the last is about – Why I chose to be a Solo Founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most humans, you might like watching a video in 2x better. Here you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;yt-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YTi5VLLYzbg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Note: Liking and Subscribing is Free on Youtube&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;co-founders&quot;&gt;Co Founders&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the biggest companies of today. Apple, Google, Microsoft, Netflix, Facebook, Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of them have more than founders. Why is that a trend? Because there are many benefits to having more than one founders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;co-founder-benefits&quot;&gt;Co-Founder Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably know most of them, but do you know all? Let’s take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-work-distribution--complementary-skills&quot;&gt;1. Work Distribution + Complementary skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious one is complementing each other with different disciplines needed in Startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many kinds of splits, and any of the following disciplines are a great fit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raising Capital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in that order of significance (at least according to me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-emotional-support&quot;&gt;2. Emotional Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/53vLwXKBbmeic/giphy.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pulp Fiction had many lessons. Look at how they support each other!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re down, they might be up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they are down, you better be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any journey, emotional support is one of the most critical components of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing motivation to complete something we started is often due to lack of motivation, and having co-founders reduces those possibilities (except of course when everyone is down).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-brainstorm-ideas&quot;&gt;3. Brainstorm ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily that your cofounders are smarter than you (although they should be), even talking out loud and being heard can bring some insightful ideas and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-focus&quot;&gt;4. Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/l0K4i4Cm18z1X1t16/giphy.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, deep down you want this.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, your friends, and everyone else has tonnes of ideas.
Digression is easy. It’s the evil. Having co-founders can help everyone stay on course whenever there’s a distraction. Be it an idea, or a fun ploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having more ideas than bandwidth, feature creep, deprioritizing important things are just some of the common digressions. Having a cofounding team helps keeps everyone accountable and focused on one goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-push&quot;&gt;5. Push&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/ZJFmfvMutiQ0M/giphy.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Push.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cofounders mean commitment. You commited to doing X, where is it? When would Y be done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re feeling low, unmotivated, this camaraderie can help give you that nudge enough to reach ignition temperature of enthusiasm and excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-have-fun-on-the-journey&quot;&gt;6. Have fun on the journey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/CjP6x9rW7LET6dEbJr/giphy.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, deep down you want this.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gone to an amusement park alone? You’d notice that it’s a lot more fun when you’re with friends. It can, to be honest, suck going there alone. The reason is because something is fun when you get to share it with others who also experienced it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building something is not an act, it’s a process; a journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re on this journey with people that you have bond with, you’d have more memories, and a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;co-founder-drawbacks&quot;&gt;Co-Founder Drawbacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it has its cons too! Some of them big enough to make it a really bad experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read through everything before jumping into a work marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-hunt-is-hard&quot;&gt;a. Hunt is Hard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a co founder, you’d end up finding one, and it’s not easy. You’ll spend lot of energy and time. It’s always best if you met someone in college, or worked with them in a team, and then later on decided to start the company together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have anyone like that, then searching for people can take a lot of time, energy, and frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;b-decision-making&quot;&gt;b. Decision Making&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you ever have a manager who won’t understand what you’re saying, and you have to convince them to do something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you watched a movie where the Protagonist is stuck explaining to their bosses that the world will come to an end if they don’t evacuate now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, an introvert-ish personality, it can be frustrating, time and energy consuming to convince someone when you need to make a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the biggest drawbacks of having Co Founders. If they are not aligned on the same page, then convincing them can take more time and energy than actually trying something out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;c-too-much-discussion-too-little-action&quot;&gt;c. Too Much Discussion. Too Little Action.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a new feature? You could spend entire day, or days, or even weeks just “discussing” it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too much documentation, chats, discussions, push backs, all of them can make you really slow, instead of actually making what you intended to in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a startup, it’s almost always more fruitful to take action, than to “discuss”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lot of things are limited in startups, most important of them: time and energy. You must do everything to conserve these two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dependencies&quot;&gt;Dependencies.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to r/startups, you’d find 1 out of 4 posts is about them wanting out, or their co-founders leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There could any number of reasons, from personal situation, to change in mindset or things just not working out between the co founders / product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you worked super hard in setting up the marketing for the product. There’s lot of great content, partnership deals with Creators, and SEO content to go with it. But… the tech co-founder decides to leave the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do next? Your startup might not work any more because you don’t have the product and finding a new cofounder can take ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dependency can be dangerous, and if you don’t know anything about some part of the work, it’s possible that if one of the cards is removed, the entire pyramid falls apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally you’d like enough exposure that even if one of the co-founders decides to leave, you know how to take things forward, or find the right resources for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mismatch&quot;&gt;Mismatch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep reading the phrase “Toxic environment” in different posts. If your co-founders have a different mindset in the long term vision, or difficult attitude, all of it can lead to a Toxic environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the reason you started a company? It was to define and set the culture, but if you’re stuck with co-founders who don’t match the culture you wanted, what do you do? You can’t fire them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you just leave your incredible idea for the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-a-drawback&quot;&gt;“Not a Drawback”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listed all the drawbacks, but one thing I want to underline is something that’s not a drawback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t make your decision of not having co-founders because you might have to split the equity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, 10% of 10 million » 100% of $0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solo-founder-benefits&quot;&gt;Solo Founder Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the drawbacks of co-founders are essentially Solo Founder advantages. I won’t repeat them and only include things not included above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-learn-learn&quot;&gt;Learn Learn Learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are you doing a startup anyways? You could get a job at FAANG or some big company in your field and earn a lot there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you get to learn a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy learning, you’ll love the journey of doing things alone because they will be exponential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From writing code to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drawbacks-of-being-a-solo-founder&quot;&gt;Drawbacks of being a Solo Founder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the list is way too-ooo long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;youll-work-a-lot&quot;&gt;You’ll work a lot.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt this one needs any explanation whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fail-a-lot-alone&quot;&gt;Fail a lot. Alone.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing is part of the journey. But failing alone can suck. When you fail at something together, it’s easier to laugh it off, and push each other to march ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what when you’re alone? There’s no laugh, only failure, and trust me it can hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-emotional-support&quot;&gt;No emotional support.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness increases by sharing, and sorrow decreases. But if you have no-one to share with, there’s no emotional support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;doubtful-investors-and-rightly-so&quot;&gt;Doubtful Investors, and Rightly So.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accelerators, and investors in general recommend having co-founders. This is in part because they understand how hard it is to build and run a startup alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;master-of-all&quot;&gt;Master of ALL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/eBQqrM0MCGJhu/giphy-downsized-large.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yes, deep down you want this.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a lone founder, you must known at least part of everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have an idea?
You should know how to design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to build?
You should know how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to production?
Well, you should know how to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to market?
You should know how to market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create content?
You should know how to make videos, and write blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get revenue?
You should know how to create funnels and close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hire? Taxes? Administration? Raising Capital?
…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point being, solo founders need to know everything, as everything in the startup process is an important discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-did-i-chose-to-start-be-a-solo-founder&quot;&gt;Why did I chose to start be a solo founder&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given so many benefits of having co-founders, you must be wondering, why did I choose to go solo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-i-didnt-really-have-an-option&quot;&gt;Well, I didn’t really have an option&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the connections I had at this point&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personality-trait&quot;&gt;Personality Trait&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just observing my life experiences, I realized, and came to terms with, that I’m really efficient when I work alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best things, and breakthroughs have happened in the moments when I was alone, and with time I accepted and embraced this reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;love-for-learning&quot;&gt;Love for Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love learning meaningful things, and going through this experience has expanded my horizons beyond what I would have thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I know everything necessary from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I successful? That depends on definition, but have I learnt a lot? You bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;which-path-should-you-choose&quot;&gt;Which path should you choose?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most great answers, the answer to this question is also: “It Depends”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 90% cases I’d suggest that should start a company with a cofounder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at your personality. What do you really value? Why are you starting a company, or building a product?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know someone that could fill the things you have little experience in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you willing to learn everything? You can’t hire someone to do it for you, even if you do, you’d need to know it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never black and white, but the one thing I recommend is to get started and take some action. It’s the only correct answer. Well, for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, keep the equity out of the reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;curious-about-what-i-am-building&quot;&gt;Curious about what I am building?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m building YRL - a marketing platform that makes it super easy for Businesses and Creators to partner on the basis of Cost per Click / Conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;customized-button&quot; onclick=&quot; window.open(&apos;https://getyrl.com/business&apos;,&apos;_blank&apos;)&quot;&gt;
YRL for Businesses
&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/solo-cofounders/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/solo-cofounders/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Startup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&apos;The Unconventional Founder&apos; Youtube Channel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After overcoming a deeply rooted resistance, I finally started a Youtube channel. This post explains why it was so difficult, and what understanding convinced me to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe we learn better with visuals than reading, so here you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;yt-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UPbJG26Y9iE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;Namastey! Like and Subscribe :)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still prefer to read? Read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hesitation&quot;&gt;The Hesitation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been deeply inspired by great tech founders from Larry Page, to Elon Musk. From Steve Jobs to Jeff Bezos. All of them have built incredible products and companies, though none of them have been active content creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everytime you see a video of them on Youtube, 99% of the times it would be that of an interview in a conference. The rest 1% is when they are introducing / launching a product to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the founders of Youtube all the way to founders of Alphabet / Google, none of them have actively created content themselves (except of course, the first video on Youtube).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few simple reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating Content takes time, which tech founders could be spending in building products, teams and scaling their services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology startup founders usually have a different type of personality than those of content creators.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In tech sector, even today, writing is a much more preferred medium, and a more powerful way of conveying messages to the world, with Audio only podcasts as probably the closest cousin. No wonder Elon Musk sticks to Twitter, and so do 99.9% of other people in tech industry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tech founders and engineers prefer to be private in general. You’d never really know where these founders are, or how they are spending their time. It’s probably because they understand technology and its drawbacks way more than most people can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s better to be wealthy and anonymous than to be rich and famous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always identified myself to be one of those founders that remain private, away from public eye. Spending time hacking problems that impacted everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the last few months, something changed. As if a button flipped, and all of a sudden I wanted to be a content creator. A Youtuber as it aligns the most with my personality, and very committed to creating videos about anything and everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-switch-flip&quot;&gt;The Switch Flip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There wasn’t one single moment, but a lots of them that one after the other just kept blowing up my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-share-mistakes-and-learnings&quot;&gt;1. Share Mistakes and Learnings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a technology startup founder, if there’s one thing I’ve been doing consistently is making mistakes, and learning from them. When you undergo an experience like that, there’s an internal voice that wants to share those learnings with someone who may find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s more stylish and pep thing to be a startup founder today than it has ever been. There’s an exponential increase in the number of startups worldwide, and I believe we are still at the beginning of this global explosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single year to come, there will be more entrepreneurs than there have ever been in the past, which means if I share my learnings, the potential audience that might benefit from those learnings will continue to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-give-back&quot;&gt;2. Give Back&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like you and everyone else today, most of what I’ve learned is from others online. Be it through Blogs or Youtube videos, then why shouldn’t I give something in return as well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-not-enough-practical-channels&quot;&gt;3. Not enough Practical Channels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of channels on youtube that teach how to write code. There are also lot of channels which talk about startup “wisdom”. But I still feel the gap between the two categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still not enough video content that takes someones from coming up with an idea, all the way through executing it IRL. There’s a lot of content that does this well but it’s spread sparsely through blogs, and reddit posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hopeful that I can help in reducing this gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-yrl--get-yrl-go-viral&quot;&gt;4. YRL : Get Yrl, Go Viral!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built a product called YRL (&lt;a href=&quot;getyrl.com&quot;&gt;getyrl.com&lt;/a&gt;), where Businesses and Creators can partner with Cost per Click and Cost per Conversion campaigns. It’s blazing fast, simple and easy to use. I’d call it Robinhood of digital and affiliate marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;customized-button&quot; onclick=&quot; window.open(&apos;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgumVa37_24jNvYizs7kUiw&apos;,&apos;_blank&apos;)&quot;&gt;
Checkout YRL →
&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the product as a Business because marketing a product is really hard today thanks to the ocean of content online. But the story was still incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YRL is not just for Businesses, its more for Creators. If I want to make YRL successful, being a Business is not enough. I should be a content creator myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-pushing-comfort-zone&quot;&gt;5. Pushing Comfort Zone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recording, Editing, Publishing, and Promoting content in its entirety is a different ball game than anything related to writing code, thinking of architecture. or building a product. Coding skills don’t help at all to be honest (trust me I tried making videos using Python!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning each of these bits is a new challenge for me, and a big way to grow personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-its-unconventional&quot;&gt;6. It’s Unconventional&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are channels for almost every type of content, it’s still pretty new for founders of tech startups to post content online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because historically, the personality type of tech founders has been very different from that of content creators (Youtubers for example). There are probably a handful of tech founders who are actively creating videos online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds unconventional, and thus my calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-new-territory&quot;&gt;7. New Territory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making Youtube videos is a new territory for me and it comes with its own challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From learning how to record, edit and create engaging content, to how to get more views, likes and subscribers, there are more things to learn in Content Creation than I could have ever imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-passive-income-source&quot;&gt;8. Passive Income Source&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the stock investments, I don’t really have any passive income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hopeful that at some point creating content would bring in some passive income to support my entrepreneurial journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-run-marketing-experiments&quot;&gt;9. Run Marketing Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I could run not one, two but thousand different marketing experiments? As a founder it sounds incredibly exciting. This is true for social media and making videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to run so many experiments, feels like a super power to me, and I’m really excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-ability-to-convey-ideas&quot;&gt;10. Ability to Convey Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above reasons are valid and good reasons, but the biggest reason why I want to solve is because I want to learn how to convey ideas that stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It the most important part of any successful startup, probably the only one, and if I can master it, I can make not one but many, many successful products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-journey-begins&quot;&gt;The Journey Begins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here I go, the next phase of my journey -&amp;gt; making popular videos online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already, don’t miss your chance at 10 years of good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like and subscribe to my Youtube channel 👇&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button class=&quot;customized-button&quot; onclick=&quot; window.open(&apos;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgumVa37_24jNvYizs7kUiw&apos;,&apos;_blank&apos;)&quot;&gt;
“The Unconventional Founder”
&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/becoming-a-creator/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/becoming-a-creator/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Youtube</category>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Product Lessons from $1 Lint Remover</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a great product user experience? This article shares the product lessons hidden in mighty Lint removers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-black-jeans-looks-ugly&quot;&gt;My black jeans looks ugly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago during a call with my friend, I was asked a simple question: &lt;em&gt;how to remove white particles (lint) from brand new black jeans?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend who I was on call with, had recently bought a black pair of jeans. Right after leaving home he realized that it was full of lint which made this brand new pair look like an old used jeans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem is quite simple if you know the solution, but if you don’t know how to solve it, I promise that it’s one of the hardest challenges humans have faced in the field of personal image and self confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-seinfeld-was-indian-there-would-be-a-show-on-lint&quot;&gt;If Seinfeld was Indian, there would be a show on Lint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in India, I witnessed lint as a big problem. It’s just that neither I, nor anyone I knew had a solution to it. Lint always appeared on woolen coats during winter seasons and affected everyone without a bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exposed to brushing the coats, the only known solution, which seldom made a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year after year, people would buy expensive coats for winter, and soon they’d be destroyed by varying kinds of &lt;em&gt;lint&lt;/em&gt;. On special events, helpless and without a choice, people would wear their fancy &lt;em&gt;linted&lt;/em&gt; coats that looked old and worn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if this was one of the reasons why my mother never let me buy black clothes (this and the summer heat).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago when I first moved to the US, my another Indian friend had proudly introduced me to &lt;strong&gt;the lint remover&lt;/strong&gt;. He got it from Dollar Tree, and the joy on his face sharing this discovery with me was the same as if he had won a lottery. He (and now I) had discovered the solution to a decade old problem that affected our self confidence; perhaps still does to a billion+ people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aha-its-magic&quot;&gt;Aha! It’s magic!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Back to present.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the ongoing call with my friend, I shared my profound wisdom and exposed him to the mighty lint remover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 20 minutes I got a call back from him. “It’s magic!” he exclaimed. I vicariously relived the joy in that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/great-ux/wow.gif&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Aha!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We next discussed what a great user experience is, and how I should focus on creating products that bring out a similar Aha moment in users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-a-great-product&quot;&gt;What’s a great product?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great product isn’t necessarily the one that uses ground breaking technology. It’s the one that solves a real world problem for users – very simply. It doesn’t matter how many users use it, for each one of them the experience by itself should bring joy, relief, and a feeling of eureka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/great-ux/roller.jpg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mightly Lint Remover&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lint remover -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;solves a real world problem that affects most people who wear clothes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;takes few seconds to understand and few steps to use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;can be used anywhere, and is independent of any other technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;immediately solves the problem, with impact highly visible to the user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;is cheap, uses simple technology that is easy to produce and scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Youtube, Search, or Video Chat applications may not feel like &lt;em&gt;eureka!&lt;/em&gt; to us anymore, but try to imagine what emotions they bring to someone who has never used these products before, better yet, never imagined their existence. It’s a feeling of joy and wonder that has the sound &lt;em&gt;“Aha!”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course these are high tech products, but they are nowhere close to discovering uranium, or successful genetic cloning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I talk about Lint removers as a generic product, not a product from X company which is sturdy and fits in travel bag. In this sense Lint Removers can be considered as an invention. Most startups creating new unconventional products fall in a similar category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-projects-fail-the-lint-removers-baseline&quot;&gt;My projects fail the Lint Remover’s baseline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the discussion with my friend, I started to think: why has he never called me up after testing my early stage projects? Why am I not building things that bring out the same emotions in him as does a $1 lint remover?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment I felt dejected. In a few minutes I had the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Lint remover was such a great product, why did it take my friend so long to discover it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend had this eureka moment, not because Lint remover is a great product. He had this moment because he found it when he had a &lt;em&gt;pressing problem problem at hand&lt;/em&gt;, affecting him personally. If I shared the same product with my friend when he was wearing blue jeans, I doubt he would have had the same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, creating a great incredible product isn’t sufficient. The lint remover doesn’t become &lt;em&gt;mighty&lt;/em&gt; lint remover until it reaches people who are experiencing the problem it solves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/great-ux/design.jpg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Creation isn&apos;t enough&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distribution, availability, and introduction &lt;strong&gt;at the time of need&lt;/strong&gt; are, if not more, as important to the product as the invention itself. Could this be the reason why my friend hasn’t called me to share the Aha! moment he had while testing my projects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of a creator doesn’t end at creating the product that’s cheap, simple, scalable, does the job well etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job of a creator ends when the user in need &lt;em&gt;discovers&lt;/em&gt;, uses the product to solve a problem and says &lt;em&gt;‘Aha! It’s magic.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/great-user-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/great-user-experience/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Product</category>
        
        <category>Gyaan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namaste</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to sudcha.com! This is the first post of the blog and I’d like to share how this site came into existence, and what purpose it serves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site will host my experiences, learnings and thoughts to the potential reader(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I never really thought of writing content on my own site. Instead I always believed that it makes more sense to write for the products I am/was building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month I wrote a blog post on our company blog: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/&quot;&gt;“We burnt $72K and almost went bankrupt”&lt;/a&gt; which &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; went viral. There were definitely more than 72K views on the blog post, and it was translated to more than few languages on popular sites across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I published the blog on our company blog because it was connected to our company’s journey. It was after publishing the blog post that I realized that there’s so much I could share, most of which won’t be a good fit for the company blog but definitely acceptable on my own, which brings us to this blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sudcha.com&quot;&gt;blog.sudcha.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;topics-and-periodicity&quot;&gt;Topics and Periodicity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog isn’t for a particular niche, because honestly I’m all over the place. I intend to cover topics from business, engineering, technology and random rants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing isn’t my first priority, and for this reason, many of my posts may be sporadic, and about past events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everything-is-an-expression&quot;&gt;Everything is an expression&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that everything in the universe is an expression. In fact, the universe itself is an expression of itself. For us humans who have relatively more choice and freedom than other species, everything we do is to express ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/general/expression.jpg&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid black&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Everything is an expression.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From how we drive, dress, write, create and share, everything is an expression of our existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is a channel for my expressions based on my learnings and experiences. I hope the posts here provide some value to the world who has given me so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-posts&quot;&gt;Future Posts?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to get updates, you can subscribe with your email address at the end of this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternately, you can also &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/contact&quot;&gt;connect with me&lt;/a&gt; and I’ll post everytime there’s a new blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;love-and-hate&quot;&gt;Love and Hate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no comment section on the blog yet, but depending on how popular (or unpopular) it gets, I might consider adding it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how good or bad the content is, there shouldn’t be room for hate. If you don’t like the content, you can simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=cute+kitten&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like it, &lt;strong&gt;share it&lt;/strong&gt;, add references to it, and keep reading on :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/namaste/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000http://localhost:4000/namaste/</guid>
        
        
        <category>General</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
